<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>io.github.finite_galaxy.finite_galaxy</id>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">finite-galaxy.desktop</launchable>
  <name>Finite Galaxy</name>
  <summary>A free and open source space exploration game.</summary>
  <developer_name>Finite Galaxy</developer_name>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0 AND CC-BY-SA-4.0 AND CC-BY-SA-3.0 AND CC-BY-3.0 AND CC-BY-2.0</project_license>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <description>
  <p>
    Explore other star systems. Earn money by trading, carrying passengers, or completing missions. Use your earnings to buy a better ship or to upgrade the weapons and engines on your current one. Blow up pirates. Take sides in a civil war. Or leave human space behind and hope to find some friendly aliens whose culture is more civilized than your own...
  </p>
  <p>
    Finite Galaxy is is a free and open source space exploration game; it is derived from Michael Zahniser's Endless Sky, a game similar to Elite, Escape Velocity, or Star Control. You start out as the captain of a tiny space ship and can choose what to do from there. The game includes a major plot line and many minor missions, but you can choose whether you want to play through the plot or strike out on your own as a merchant or bounty hunter or explorer.
  </p>
  </description>
  <categories>
    <category>Game</category>
    <category>Free and open source</category>
    <category>Simulation</category>
  </categories>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/finite-galaxy/finite-galaxy/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/finite-galaxy/finite-galaxy/wiki</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/finite-galaxy/finite-galaxy</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://endless-sky.github.io/images/screenshots/battle.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://endless-sky.github.io/screenshots/beams.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://camo.githubusercontent.com/647979e73d2121a1a982a96b0561e0e435598fd4/68747470733a2f2f656e646c6573732d736b792e6769746875622e696f2f73637265656e73686f74732f736d616c6c382e6a7067</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://endless-sky.github.io/images/screenshots/outfitter.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://endless-sky.github.io/images/screenshots/shipyard.jpg</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.9.8" date="2018-10-18">
      <description>
        <p>Game mechanics:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Hyperjump fuel depends on ship's effective total mass, i.e. hull mass + outfits + cargo + fighters</li>
          <li>Installed outfits can no longer be plundered by default</li>
          <li>Introduced core space, used by energy generators and some other outfits</li>
          <li>Introduced jump heat, a percentage of a ship's maximum heat</li>
          <li>Introduced random damage attributes for all weapon damage types</li>
          <li>Minimum deprecation from 25% to 50%, time from 1000 to 365 days</li>
          <li>Self-destruct check is performed only once: upon boarding</li>
          <li>Ships consume energy based on the number of bunks, to represent life support systems</li>
          <li>Target's shields and hull are only displayed if within tactical scan range</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Game content:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Removed news and portraits</li>
          <li>Removed conversation scenes</li>
          <li>Removed planetary defence fleets and tribute</li>
          <li>Ship categories now depend on ship's total mass</li>
          <li>Ship explosion blast radius = total mass / 5</li>
          <li>Ships have zero fuel capacity by default</li>
          <li>Planets are twice as large</li>
          <li>Distances between planets are trebled</li>
          <li>Non-missile weapons have their range increased by about a third</li>
          <li>Missile weapons are more powerful but have reduced capacity</li>
          <li>More regional specialization by redistributing many ships and outfits</li>
          <li>Several new outfits; others were deprecated</li>
          <li>Hundreds of ship, outfits, mission, events, and map tweaks</li>
        </ul>
        <p>User interface:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Changed font to Linux Libertine Display</li>
          <li>Used a space as thousands separator</li>
          <li>Numbers display up to three decimals by default</li>
          <li>Display per shot and per second weapon values on the same line in the outfit info panel</li>
          <li>Display many more stats in the ship info panel</li>
          <li>Ship details in shop above fleet overview instead of below</li>
          <li>Fleet overview from four to five ship icon columns</li>
          <li>More view zoom out levels</li>
          <li>More map zoom levels</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Under the hood:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Plug-ins can add, remove, and reorder outfit and ship categories</li>
          <li>More swizzle options</li>
          <li>Reorganized files</li>
          <li>Replaced tabs with two spaces</li>
          <li>C++14</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Bug fixes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>A few minor things.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="drugs-alcohol">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
</component>
